Now let's learn how to make a foldable pocket.
First of all, we still use the basic pocket version.
Here I changed it to pink.
It's more convenient for you to identify this pocket version.
First, we select the line on both sides.
Press the Shift key to select more.
Then right-click and select the line that is created according to the curve.
Let's draw a middle line.
This middle line is where we are going to start folding later.
Right-click here and select Cut.
When cutting, the middle line will not automatically form a line.
This is what we want.
Now this pocket is divided into the left half and the right half.
The bottom line here, let's delete it first.
Or reactivate first.
Right-click when selecting these lines.
Select the reactivate line panel.
When the line is reactivated, it will no longer work.
We can pull these two panels apart.
Then we will start.
Let's start making the part of the pocket folding.
First of all, because the panel is relatively soft now,
it may not be very convenient for folding panels.
Let's harden the panel first.
Make it look like a piece of paper.
This way we can easily apply some folding functions that we will use later.
Then we are going to start the part of paper folding.
First of all, let's consider whether the panel is folded outward or inward.
Here we will make an example of folding inward.
First of all, we can click on the panel in the 3D window.
Then change the inner line according to the blue index point.
This is where we will fold in later.
Then we need to copy this panel.
First of all, here we can use the adjustment panel tool to select the entire panel.
Copy and paste.
After copying the panel,
we will arrange it in the 2D window.
After arranging it,
cut off this line.
Then delete the excess part.
We only keep the part of the right side here for folding.
Then we move this panel in the 3D window.
Hide it behind this panel.
After that, we will start to prepare the box.
Before the box,
we need to adjust the small folding panel on the inner layer.
First of all,
the main panel on the outer layer must be facing the front.
So the panel that is folded back should be facing the back.
After we put the sides together,
it will be in the correct direction.
Here we will turn the panel horizontally.
Then move it to the inner side of the original panel.
After that,
we use the adjustment panel tool to sew the sides together.
If you are not sure where to sew,
we can use the support point in the 3D window to sew.
After we sew this panel,
you will see that this panel will automatically turn over.
This is because we did not set the folding angle for the panel line here.
The folding angle of the model is 180.
180 is equal to flat.
Here we set its folding angle to 0.
Then it will fold well.
It is the same as the one we used to make the workbook pocket.
However,
we used the panel line tool to select the panel line.
Then set its folding angle to 0.
This is why we have to make sure that these two panels are facing each other.
After setting the folding angle,
you can see that even if we do not print the panel line,
it can actually apply the folding angle.
It's just that after we print the panel line,
it can hold up.
It is more convenient for us to arrange and adjust.
Then we select the panel line we just connected.
Ctrl C, Ctrl R,
and create a panel line that is close to the panel line.
Because our panel line has been folded inward,
we still need to make up for the part that is folded outward.
In the storage space,
turn the panel line over,
and move it to the innermost position of the panel line we printed before.
When we place it,
you have to pay attention to whether its orientation is corresponding.
That is to say,
when we place it now,
you can see that they are facing each other.
In this way, they are correct.
Then we can click on the auxiliary point in the 3D window to create a panel line.
After creating it,
do not forget to set the folding angle of the panel line created.
But here,
it is different from the setting just now.
Because now we are facing each other,
we have to fold this panel line inward,
not outward.
So we have to set the folding angle to 360 degrees.
After folding,
we select the part of the folding that we just created,
Ctrl C, Ctrl R,
and copy it to the other side of us.
Then use the line powder tool,
the shortcut key is N,
to merge the two sides together.
After mixing,
pay attention to the newly created panel line.
It does not set the folding angle.
So here,
we have to switch to the edit panel line tool.
Find the panel line of the newly created panel line,
set its folding angle to 0,
and let it fold in the correct way.
Then finally,
we sew the middle.
Then we look at our friends here,
how much is the folding angle we apply here?
This one in the middle.
That's right,
here we don't need to adjust its folding angle,
because the middle is a flat position,
and it is flat,
so we don't need to adjust its folding angle.
Here,
let's ask again,
if it is facing out,
then the folding angle of the panel line is 0.
If it is facing in,
the folding angle of the panel line is 360.
If it is flat,
then we don't need to adjust its folding angle.
Then,
we can start to prepare for merging.
So if we can't tell how to merge,
we can use the edge panel line tool.
After selecting the panel line,
click Merge,
it will merge directly along the panel line position.
But be careful,
when merging,
our grid will have some deformation.
Because now the particle diameter is relatively large,
the number of grid is relatively small,
so there will be some deformation problems.
In addition,
we used to use the folding angle of the panel line.
Now we need to create a new inner line,
and then apply the folding angle to the inner line to fold.
And when the panel line merges,
the hardening will automatically cancel.
So here,
if we think that
the panel line is a little soft and inconvenient to fold,
we can still hardening the panel line.
Then we merge the rest of the parts.
Remember to create the inner line application folding angle after merging.
After merging here,
because our line is folded from the front to the inside,
so the folding angle of this line is 360 degrees.
Then we can hardening the panel line.
Because the panel line does not use hardening,
the force of its own will spread this panel line.
Next,
we will repeat the previous operation.
But be careful,
when you merge the panel line,
the hardening will automatically cancel.
Here,
after we merge,
it should be a flat panel line in the middle.
So here we don't need to add the inner line.
Then we continue to complete the right side panel line.
Here we merge them directly.
Then merge the inner line.
After merging the inner line,
we need to apply the folding angle to the inner line.
Let's review it again.
The line on the left is folded inward,
so it is 360 degrees.
The line on the right is folded outward,
so it is 0 degrees.
After folding,
because we merged the panel line,
we need to draw the panel line again here.
It is convenient for us to do a follow-up later.
So here we need to draw the panel line again.
Here we can see that
we now need to mix the top of it with the bottom of it.
Then we can fix the panel line.
Then we switch to the threading tool.
Here we use the free threading tool.
From the middle line,
we can click to see this blue support point.
Starting from this line,
we work in a coinciding way.
But when we move the mouse, you will see that the line on the left cannot be selected, it has no subtraction, so we select the line in the middle here and press the right button to add it to the line on the outside of the board.
After the point is formed, the sewing line can be automatically subtracted. Here we switch back to the sewing tool for sewing.
Then we use the free sewing tool to sew this point to the left and right sides of the point
In the 3D window, we will see that the sewing line is already in line, so we can open the simulation by pressing the control key.
After opening the simulation, we will use the edge sewing tool to adjust the sewing line.
Here we can see that when the two boards are folded in this way, the sewing line is folded up to be sewn, so we need to switch the sewing line type to TURN.
After that, we do this kind of regular
The fold of the fold will be folded up, remember that when the left and right are folded, its sewing line type must also be changed to TURN.
Then we switch to the other side, you can see that the other side should also be folded to the left to fix the fold.
So here we switch to the free sewing tool, after sewing to both sides, we directly change its sewing line type to TURN, so that the fold on one side is fixed.
Next, we will operate in other positions in the same way.
The same procedure is applied in the third position.
After we have finished sewing and fixing the upper and lower parts, we can proceed to the following operations.
First, we activate the sewing line that was previously back-activated, and then right-click to activate the sewing line.
Then we can start the simulation.
But in the middle of this, can you see some unstable places?
Here is an unstable line.
There is a line here, and there is a line here, and there is a line here, and there is a line here.
Then you can see that there are some unstable places. But in the middle here, can you see some unstable places? There are some unstable places.
The reason for this is because our previous powder line is the outer layer of the panel and the pocket panel together.
But now they are in the middle of a layer that we just folded in and folded out.
So here we use the edit powder line tool to select the powder line that was created before and delete it.
Then use the free powder tool to select this part of the powder line on the body first.
Then press the Shift key, because we are now going to do a multi-step division.
While pressing the Shift key and not releasing it, point from the leftmost point to the first inner line.
Then we are going to find the innermost position. The innermost position is this section between the two 360-degree lines.
Then we are going to skip the position of the fold in the middle.
If you don't know, you can click on the 3D version and then follow the blue auxiliary point.
Start from this point to the far right.
Then press the Shift key and then press the control key to simulate it.
You will see that the overall simulation is very stable now.
Because we are not doing the division in the cross-layer.
Finally, we cut out the sound and simulate it.
Next, let's learn how to make another folding pocket.
First, let's go back to the time when the pocket was not divided.
Here we apply the inner line of the special folding angle to these lines.
Return them to the 180-degree folding angle.
After we start the simulation, we will see that it is now in a flat state.
Since we are folding outward, we set the folding angle of these two inner lines in the middle to 0.
Then set the two inner lines next to these two lines to a 360-degree folding angle.
So they fold inward.
Now we see that this pocket has been folded.
And the middle part is protruding outward.
In addition, the inner line with this set folding angle of 180 degrees can also be deleted directly.
After completing the folding angle of the inner line, we can continue to sew.